Shoaib Ahmed

■ahmed.shoaib1729@gmail.com □+8801686454469 ■Shoaib Ahmed ■edge555.github.io

Google Scholar Profile - Shoaib Ahmed

Summary

I'm passionate about using my computational skills, particularly in NLP and Generative AI, to solve cognitive challenges and develop technologies that benefit people. At the same time, I'm excited about the potential to apply these technologies in Healthcare, aiming to detect diseases early, prevent them, and make healthcare more efficient.

Research & Publications

Invariant Scattering Transform for Medical Imaging

https://arxiv.org/abs/2307.04771

- Applied wavelet technique for medical image classification
- Used scattering transform to build signal representation for image classification

Education

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering

November 2017 - April 2022

Ahsanullah University of Science and Technology • CGPA 3.081 out of 4.00

Dhaka, Bangladesh

· Achieved highest marks in Data Structure, Algorithms, Database, and Software Development Labs

Undergraduate Thesis

Reportbyte: An Advanced Business Analytics System

An advanced business analytic and assistant system that provides four kinds of services (Chatbot, Question-answering bot, Data visualization tool, and Predictive data analysis tool) built with machine learning and artificial intelligence tools. **Advisor**: Mohammad Moinul Hoque, Associate Professor, Department of CSE, AUST

Experiences

Software Engineer

Cefalo (<u>mail@cefalo.com</u>)

September 2022 - Present

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Key Responsibilities:

- Integrating AI support to the project
- Actively fixed critical production bugs of overseas customers
- Implement features for a large data migration system that can process 1 billion data
- Did R&D on some complex features that improved the client's business

Software Engineer

Enosis Solutions Ltd. (info@enosisbd.com)

June 2022 - August 2022

Dhaka, Bangladesh

Key Responsibilities:

- Improved performance of Machinery Design Software with complex mathematical calculation
- Refactored some legacy code to much better maintainable code
- Made changes in an automated testing system that shortens the testing time by 15%

Trainer of Competitive Programming

Ahsanullah University of Science and Technology

January 2020 - January 2022

Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Taught algorithms and data structures to 300 students in my university's CSE department.
- Mentored the students to learn about different online judges and solve programming problems.

Educator January 2023 - Present

<u>Amar iSchool</u>

Dhaka, Bangladesh

System Design Course: Zero to Intermediate

Course Curriculum

- Computer Architecture, System Performance Metrics, Scalability, Networking Basics
- Cache, Database, REST API, Message Queue

Achievements and Participations

- Participated in more than 10 national programming contests achieving best rank of 4th place
- Solved **3900**+ Programming across all top-tier online judges
- Attended 300+ online contests among global participants
- Achieved Expert rank at Codeforcecs
- Got invited to take Google Foobar Challenge, Cleared 4 out of 5 rounds

Certifications

Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate

- Learnt to clean and organize data for analysis using spreadsheets, SQL and R programming
- Visualize and present data findings in dashboards, presentations, and commonly used visualization platforms

Involvements

Microsoft Learn Student Ambassadors

December 2019 - March 2022

Beta Ambassador

- Conducted workshop on competitive programming
- Reached global audience for programming content

AUST Programming and Informatics Club

December 2021 - January 2023

Joint Secretary

- Formed the club to increase programming activity
- Organized National Inter-University Programming Contest of 400 participants

Skills

Programming: C, C++, Python, C#, SQL

ML Libraries: Sci-Kit Learn, Numpy, Pandas, Scipy

DL Libraries: TensorFlow, PyTorch, Keras **IDE:** Jupyter, Google Colab, Visual Studio